# Dennis K. Adjei-Baah

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

445 Wawona Street, San Francisco, CA 94116

□ 314.420.8472 | ☑ dadjeibaah@gmail.com | ♠ kofi.io | ☑ deebo91 | ☐ dennisadjeibaah

## **Summary** \_

Software engineer with 3+ years of professional experience in Spring and Hibernated based server-side applications. Experienced using Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Groovy/Grails and Play with Scala. Possesses an entrepreneurial mindset. Ability to learn new technologies rapidly. Keen sense of writing clean, readable code with scalability and efficiency in mind. Prodigious work ethic and ability to accomplish individual tasks quickly. Strong values in teamwork in an agile setting. Interested in a Java Software Engineering role.

## Skills\_

**Programming** JAVA, C#.NET, Javascript, Python, Node.JS, iOS Swift, Oracle PL/SQL, MySQL, MS SQL

Web Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Play/Scala, Akka, REST APIs, Groovy/Grails, AngularJS, ASP.NET MVC, Grunt, HTML5, jQuery, Git, Bower,

LESS

IDEs & Tools Docker, AWS, Jenkins, Gradle, Maven, Intellij IDEA, Visual Studio, XCode, Sketch App

**Testing** Karma, Jasmine, Protractor, Spock Framework Testing, ScalaTest, Gatling

## **Experience**

Software Engineer May 2017 - September 2017

COMMERCE TEAM - ENGINEERING, TICKETFLY

San Francisco, California

- · Developed a marketing campaign RESTful API for Ticketfly clients that tracked large volumes of music fans' data
- · Integrated external Email Delivery REST APIs and webhooks into the Ticketfly marketing campaign platform
- Refactored monolith Grails server-side applications into small, efficient and clean Play/Scala microservices
- Developed event-driven microservices using a publish/subscribe architecture with RabbitMQ
- · Provided on-call support for the Ticketfly ticketing platform during peak ticket on-sales periods that served thousands of tickets
- Fixed high priority consumer facing bugs discovered in production

Teaching Assistant

Aug. 2016 - May 2017

DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTING, EAST TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

Johnson City, Tennessee

- · Taught basic computer concepts, internet security and the Microsoft Office Suite among 3 class periods of 25 students each
- · Fostered student engagement and class participation by using various techniques such as group discussions and current pop culture.
- · Graded student assignments and tests that evaluated their understanding of the Microsoft Office Suite and internet/networking concepts

## Software Engineer

August. 2015 - August. 2016

Johnson City, Tennessee

SHERROD LIBRARY TECHNOLOGY AND CONTENT SERVICES, EAST TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

- Created a log aggregation solution using Apache Solr and Piwik Analytics to track user behavior on the Sherrod Library website
- Developed several mockups using HTML5 and AngularJS to redesign the Sherrod Library website
- · Conducted interviews with about 30 library staff members to gather requirements for a Library Staff Portal
- Developed various scripts in XSLT, PHP and Javascript that reduced data processing of Thesis dissertations from weeks to a couple of days

#### **Full-Stack Software Engineer**

May 2013 - August 2015 and Summer

2016

SERVICE DELIVERY TEAM, WORLD WIDE TECHNOLOGY, INC

St. Louis, Missouri

- · Maintained and Refactored server-side applications that used Spring MVC and Spring JPA with Oracle PL/SQL
- · Increased greater project health and financial data visibility by developing a web app and microservice with AngularJS, Groovy/Grails
- Strengthened the company's web application security platform by implementing Novell's Identity Management Solution
- · Built quick prototypes in AngularJS and Grails for a quick feedback loop with clients to gather accurate technical requirements
- Developed fine grained customization of Employee time tracking using Groovy/Grails to help project managers better track resource allocation
- Helped outline a migration strategy to move a Groovy/Grails apps from in-house infrastructure to Cloud Foundry
- · Analyzed business processes in the supply chain warehouse in order to deliver accurate requirements in the proposed supply chain app

### **Education**

### M.S. in Computer and Information Science

Johnson City, Tennessee

EAST TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY (GPA:3.9)

Graduate Capstone: Faculty Teaching Credential System (https://goo.gl/iEzxy4)

#### **B.S. in Computer Science**

PRINCIPIA COLLEGE (GPA:3.4)

Elsah, Illinois

August. 2009 - May 2013

August. 2015 - May 2017



Sherrod Library Website, libraries.etsu.edu vehicle dispatch system (Akka/RabbitMQ demo), https://github.com/deebo91/vehicle-dispatch-system Grocery API (Spring Boot REST API demo), https://github.com/deebo91/grocery-api